Okay, the closed stance is demonstrated here.
We have this golf club here as being on line to my target, and then this club here is parallel to that line and that's where I keep my feet.
So this is a closed stance and the goal here is I'm going to have the club somewhat closed or somewhat neutral.
It's going to be perpendicular, or at a right angle to the line of the flight.
So the goal here, with the closed stance is everything is in line and I just take the club back like this and I swing.
So I just take it back and I hit that ball.
So the idea of a closed stance, it's a way of I can put more true backspin on the ball, possible a little side spin that will go to the left, so I can keep the ball on line.
Just like that.
So that ball stays really straight when I hit it.
So a closed stance is very useful.
It's a very nice shot, and it depends of course on what the lie of the green is.
So the closed stance, you want to, you can practice, you can use yardsticks or golf clubs, or I've seen some people, they've built a little device so they can keep the club.
They can stay closed and keep everything parallel, and that way they can keep their shots on line a lot better.